This production features inappropriate dialogue and smoking scenes.
（本作特點包含 極度不妥的台詞及吸菸畫面）
Hey! Wake up, ugly!
喂！起床了，醜女！
You female gorilla in heat!
整天發情的母猩猩！
I got it, okay?
我知道啦
You sleep too much for someone ugly!
明明是個醜女，是打算睡多久？
Shut up, you stupid geezer.
吵死了，臭老頭
What did you say?! Say that again!
你說什麼？有膽再說一次！
Shut up, stupid shorty!
吵死了，臭矮子！
Quit making a ruckus so early!
別一大早就哇哇大叫！
I've got low blood pressure!
我有低血壓！
Damn…
真是的
MASAHIKO KONDO
（近藤真彥）
WINTER OF 1986
（1986年，冬天）
Good morning!
早安！
You may be my daughter, but your sleeping face is ugly.
雖然是我女兒，但睡相真醜
Cut it out. You're wasting it!
別拍了，真浪費！
Did you lose it? Junko Angry Pants!
發火了嗎？發火的純子！
Huh?
什麼？
You were smoking again!
你又給我抽菸了嗎？
I splashed it with water and put it out, okay?!
我有好好澆水弄熄啦！
Old man, when are you coming home today?
大叔，你今天幾點回家？
Who?
大叔是指誰？
You, baldy.
就是你啦，禿子
I dare you to say that again!
你再說一次試試看！
You, baldy, the short old man with thinning hair who's stirring natto!
就是在那裡攪拌納豆 又矮頭髮又稀疏的大叔，禿子！
When someone dares you to repeat yourself, you go and say the exact same thing!
我叫你再說一次試試看 你只要重複說一次就好了！
You don't add extra stuff each time.
不要每次都多加幾句啦
It's so hurtful.
我被傷到了
Thinning hair? Where?
頭髮稀疏？哪裡啊？
The dedicated platforms for the Saikyo Line,
原本最東邊的埼京線專用月台
constructed on the easternmost side, will be the new Platforms 1 and 2.
變成新的一、二號線月台
Time to eat.
我開動了
Starting March 3rd, the Saikyo Line will be operating on this new platform…
埼京線的新月台將於3月3號啟用…
It's a guy, isn't it?
是因為男人吧？
What?
什麼？
Don't “what” me. It's glaringly obvious.
你還疑惑，一眼就看出來了
You're curling your hair. It's like something from Tsumiki Kuzushi.
把頭髮弄得捲捲的 你以為是演《積木崩塌》啊？
You want some hanky-panky with a guy, huh?
你是要跟男人滾床單嗎？
No way.
才不會
Listen.
你聽著
Guys who are 16 or 17 are basically all apes.
16歲、17歲的男生就是猴子 幾乎都是猴子
Once they've had a taste, it's over.
給他們嘗到一次甜頭就完了
They'll be chasing a female's ass for the rest of their lives.
他們的習性就是 一輩子都會追著女人的屁股跑
Just tell me. When are you coming home?
快說啦，你幾點回家？
Five o'clock? Six?
五點還是六點？
None o'clock.
就差一點點
Lame.
有夠難笑
Junko.
純子
Say goodbye to your mom.
記得跟媽媽說你要出門了
See you.
我出門了
You're so full of energy. Shall we go somewhere?
真有精神，去走走吧
-Then let's go see Grandpa. -Cash, please.
-那買花去爺爺那邊吧 -給我錢
You're such a good girl.
真是個好孩子
Honoring your ancestors is very important.
尊敬祖先是非常重要的事情喔
And don't forget to get ice cream.
我還要吃冰淇淋
Here.
來
She's sneaky, but a good girl.
雖然愛佔便宜，但她真是個好孩子
KATSUSHIKA WARD JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL 6
（東京都葛飾區立 第六國中）
Junko used to be so cute, though.
以前那個很可愛的純子變這樣了啊
Seriously, she's like a nutcase.
真是的，她根本是病了
Well, kids these days are precocious, after all.
畢竟現在的小鬼都很早熟
When I inspected their belongings, look what I found.
我檢查了他們的書包 竟然還搜到這種東西
Outrageous.
真是不像話
PORN PARADISE
（《色情天堂》）
F*CK TO THE TEACHER
（《上到老師》）
It's a cause for concern, isn't it, Mr. Ogawa?
真是讓人擔心呢，小川老師
Well, Ms. Oversized Tits, when was your first time?
大胸舞老師的初體驗是什麼時候？
It's Mai Takasugi!
我叫高杉舞！
That's good. That's a good one.
綽號取得真好，好妙啊
I'm hungry.
肚子餓了
Me too. Let's go get something to eat.
我也是，去吃點什麼吧
I'm craving something sweet.
我想吃甜的
Well then, how about we go to Baskin-Robbins?
那要不要去吃31冰淇淋？
I like that.
好主意
It's you, Mutchy!
阿睦學長！
Mutchy, that's me!
我是阿睦喔
I was thinking, "Who's this cute chick?" and it's you, Junko.
我還想說是哪來的美麗小妞 原來是純子啊
Did you buy yourself a motorcycle, Mutchy?
你買了機車啊？阿睦學長
It's a CBX. The one Matchy rode in Highteen Boogie.
這是CBX，“Highteen Boogie” 真彥先生騎的那台
Let me guess.
也就是說
"I'll park by the beach and spend a moment making serious love to you"?
“停在海邊 在那瞬間認真地和你親熱”？
-So cool!
-真帥！
Hey, take a photo.
來，幫我拍照
Okay.
好
Yay.
太好了
Say cheese!
笑一個！
Hey, give me a ride, Mutchy!
拜託，載我們嘛，阿睦學長！
Don't be stupid!
說什麼傻話？
It's my policy not to give rides to virgins.
我是不載處女主義
Ugh, don't make fun of me!
真是的，好失禮！
Shortstop!
游擊手！
Start!
開始！
What?
什麼？
Stop it with your body, idiot!
用身體接住啊，蠢貨！
If you focus, it won't hurt you, moron!
只要集中精神 被打中也不會受傷啦，笨蛋！
Yes, sir!
是！
Your stance is too high!
腰不夠低！
Do bunny hops around the ground!
給我兔子跳一圈！
Yes, sir!
是！
What?!
什麼？
You, four-eyes!
喂，那個戴眼鏡的！
Sir?
怎麼了？
-No drinking water during practice. -Yes, sir.
-練習時不准喝水 -是
Drinking water wears you out.
喝水會更累
Yes, sir.
是
You're all getting spanked with a baseball bat!
用球棒打屁股！
Collective responsibility!
連坐處罰！
Thank you, sir!
謝謝指導！
TOEI BUS, SCHOOL-6-URA BOUND FOR KODAI SEIMON-MAE
（都營公車，六中裏 往工大正門前）
The bus is departing. Please be careful.
車子要開了，請小心
The next stop is Bunri Yonchome.
下一站，文利四丁目
We are stopping at Hanemaki.
停靠羽卷站
The bus is departing. Please be careful.
車子要開了，請小心
Hey, miss.
那邊的妹妹
Udon noodles. Udon noodles are hanging from your ears.
有烏龍麵，烏龍麵從你耳朵垂下來了
We are stopping at Bunri Yonchome.
停靠文利四丁目站
The bus is departing. Please be careful.
車子要開了，請小心
What? What is it?
什麼？有什麼事嗎？
You want me to open the window?
窗戶打開比較好嗎？
The next stop is Shiga Icchome.
-衣服都要沾到菸味了 -下一站，志賀一丁目
What is it?
怎樣啦？
You people are way weirder than I am.
你們才奇怪
Udon noodles are hanging from your ears.
你耳朵裡掛著一條烏龍麵
And you got seaweed dangling from your ears.
大叔，從耳朵裡跑出鹿尾菜了
Don't ignore me!
你有聽到吧？
Secondhand smoking!
二手菸！
-What? -Secondhand smoking!
-什麼？ -二手菸！
Hey, mister!
等一下，爺爺！
Secondhand smoking?
二手菸？
Don't provoke him. What if he's got a knife?
很危險，要是他身上有刀怎麼辦？
If I get sick from secondhand smoke, it's going to be your fault.
要是被二手菸影響健康，就是你害的
-Secondhand smoke? -Stop it. What if he stabs you?
-二手菸？ -不行，你會被刺的
You got a problem? There's an ashtray here.
你有意見嗎？這裡有菸灰缸
And there's no sign saying no smoking anywhere.
而且到處都沒有寫禁菸啊
Come on, this situation is weird.
等等，這樣太奇怪了吧
You're the dangerous one.
妹妹才比較危險
Udon noodles are hanging from your ears, and your panties are almost showing.
有烏龍麵從耳朵垂下來 還穿這種快看到內褲的裙子
-It's like you're asking to be groped. -What?!
-不就是要別人來騷擾你嗎？ -什麼？
You can't complain if that happens.
就算被人摸也不能抱怨
How outrageous!
你在胡說什麼？
That's sexual harassment! Unbelievable!
-這是性騷擾！不敢相信！ -停靠志賀一丁目
What? Did I say something wrong?
什麼？我有說得那麼過分嗎？
Run!
快逃！
I'm getting off!
我要下車！
Huh? I'm getting off too.
什麼？我也要下車
Uh-huh.
好
Six o'clock, right?
六點對吧？
I can totally make it. Yeah.
一定來得及啦，對
Very Berry Strawberry, hands down.
超莓草莓口味是唯一選擇
It's yummy, isn't it?
那很好吃吧？
Let me have a bite.
給我一口
Watch it! Pay attention to where you're going!
真危險！走路不看路啊？
Take your earplugs out.
把耳塞拿下來啦
Sorry.
抱歉
Pay for her chocolate mint ice cream.
賠一球薄荷巧克力口味的
I don't have any cash with me right now.
我身上沒有現金
-Huh?
什麼？
If you don't have cash, what do you have, then?
沒帶現金，那你身上有什麼？
Um…
-這個嘛… -真是的
Forget it.
算了啦
Go on.
走吧
Junko…
純子
This sucks.
真倒楣
What is that?
那是什麼？
Oh, damn! Junko's going to have hanky-panky!
啊，糟糕！純子要滾床單了！
Hanky-panky!
滾床單…
CAFE &amp; BAR SCANDAL
（緋聞咖啡廳、酒吧）
MUTSUGORO COMMUNICATING WITH A CHIMPANZEE
（和黑猩猩心意相通的彈塗魚先生）
If you were to date someone, you'd go for someone older, right?
要交往的話 果然還是要選比自己大的吧？
What about Kiyohara from PL?
PL的清原呢？
He was born in Showa 42, so he's two years ahead of us.
他是昭和42年生的，大我兩歲
Kuwata was born before April 1st, so he's one year ahead of us.
桑田比較早生，所以大我一歲
I don't like Kuwata.
我討厭桑田
Kiyohara is cute. Especially his double tooth.
清原很可愛，他有虎牙
What about that guy, you know,
那個人呢？你們也知道
the one with the curly hair from Tonda Couple?
他有自然捲，演過《飛翔的情侶》
Shingo Tsurumi?
鶴見辰吾？
He's got curly hair too, but there's another guy.
他也是自然捲，但不是還有一個嗎？
He was in School in the Crosshairs and The Girl Who Leapt Through Time.
有演《被狙擊的學園》 和《跳躍吧！時空少女》的自然捲男
Kishin Shinoyama?
篠山紀信？
-He's got curly hair too, but… -Ben Wada.
-雖然他也是自然捲… -和田勉
-They've all got curly hair. -Toshinori Omi.
-別只說有自然捲的人啦 -尾美利德
Him!
沒錯！
Toshinori Omi, born in Showa 40. He's 20 years old.
尾美利德先生 昭和40年出生，現在20歲
Please
請你跟我
be my girlfriend.
交往吧
-Huh?!
-什麼？
Okay, hold on.
知道了，你等一下
You're still in junior high school, right?
你是國中生吧？
Yes, the second year of junior high.
對，國中二年級生
Is it a no?
不行嗎？
Sure.
好啊
Junko!
純子！
Don't you know?
你不曉得嗎？
Her father…
她的父親…
is School 6's Ogawa from Hell.
是六中的地獄小川
Miss, I want a hi-lite!
大姐，給我hi-lite！
Pardon?
什麼？
A hi-lite! Hurry!
hi-lite啊！動作快！
My daughter is going to have hanky-panky!
我女兒要滾床單了！
I'm sorry, could you give me the number?
不好意思，請告訴我號碼
A hi-lite! You have one, don't you?
hi-lite！這裡有吧？
Why are there so many?
香菸還真多種
When did you start selling cigarettes, anyway?
話說這裡什麼時候變成香菸店了？
When I passed by this morning, this place was a dry cleaner.
我早上經過時還是洗衣店
Is this it?
是這款嗎？
It is.
就是這個
-The age verification button, please. -What?
-請按下年紀確認按鈕 -什麼？
Do I look underage to you?
我看起來像未成年嗎？
Damn it! You better take responsibility for this!
可惡！你給我負責！
If Junko has hanky-panky, it's on you!
要是純子滾床單就是你的錯！
Hanky-panky?
滾床單？
I mean, rumpy-pumpy!
就是做那檔子事啦！
It's 520 yen.
要付520圓
Are you mocking me?
你瞧不起人嗎？
CAFE &amp; BAR SCANDAL
（緋聞咖啡廳、酒吧）
A landline?
“03”？
You could come over now.
現在來我家也可以
Don't, Junko.
別這樣啦，純子
My place is nearby and my dad isn't home.
我家很近，我爸也不在家
Want to have hanky-panky with me?
想不想要滾床單？
Junko's going to have some rumpy-pumpy!
再不快點，純子要做那檔子事了…
Rumpy-pumpy!
那檔子事…
Junko!
純子…
Jun…
純…
SHONEN JUMP
（《週刊少年JUMP》 《航海王》）
Where's Fist of the North Star or Shape Up Ran?
《北斗之拳》呢？ “SHAPE UP RAN”呢？
What? Wait.
什麼？給我等一下
ISSUE 2, 2024 SHUEISHA
（第二期，2024年，集英社）
Twenty twenty-four?
“2024年”？
What the…
怎麼會…
W-What's your deal?
有什麼事嗎？
Huh? Sorry, I was just thirsty.
什麼？抱歉，我口渴了
I worked hard all day
為了這一杯
for this one glass.
我今天努力了一整天
And yet…
可是…
Huh?!
搞什麼？
Can't a mother with a baby enjoy even a single glass of beer?
難道帶嬰兒的母親 連喝杯啤酒都不行嗎？
I've been insulted by the people at the ward office and a lawyer.
在區公所被數落了一頓 又被律師臭罵一頓
I said sorry, didn't I?
所以我不是在道歉了嗎？
My baby finally fell asleep.
這孩子不久前終於睡著了
My baby finally fell asleep and hushed down,
終於睡著了，終於安靜了下來
and I thought I could finally catch a break.
我想說終於能喘口氣了
What's your deal?
你想怎樣？
There's no need to cry. It was just a single glass of beer.
只不過是一杯啤酒，沒必要哭吧
Here, miss, just have another glass.
來，小妞，來喝一杯
No, thank you.
不用了
The bill, please.
麻煩結帳
That thing?
那是什麼？
What is that sleek thing?
感覺很光滑的物品到底是什麼？
Everyone has one. Is it the latest trend?
大家都有，這很流行嗎？
Stay away.
住手
I need to pee.
我去尿尿
Don't go yet. I'll buy you a glass of beer.
別回去喔，我請你喝一杯啤酒
Barkeep!
老闆！
A beer for this lady.
給這位女性一杯啤酒
Barkeep?
老闆？
Yes?
怎麼了？
You're the barkeep? Liar.
你是老闆？少騙人了
Wait here. I'll be right back.
等我喔，我馬上回來
What's going on?
到底是怎麼回事？
The 40th anniversary?
“40週年”？
Kyon Kyon isn't that old.
Kyon Kyon不可能那麼老吧
What the hell?
怎麼回事？
Huh?
不會吧？
"NAGISA NO HAIKARA NINGYO" KYOKO KOIZUMI
（《沙灘上的摩登人魚》 小泉今日子）
Speak of the devil, and here comes Ogawa from Hell.
才剛提到，地獄小川就出現了
SPORTS JAPAN
（《日本運動》）
SHOWA 61 (1986) JANUARY 18TH SATURDAY
（昭和61年，1986年 1月18日星期六）
Hey, where's the woman?
我問你，那女人呢？
She was drinking beer here.
就是坐在這喝啤酒的那個人
The woman?
女人？
Beer?
啤酒？
She was right here. A mother with a baby. She seemed to have baggage.
她在啊，帶著一個嬰兒的媽媽 好像有什麼隱情的樣子
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
She's not here?
她不在這裡？
I see.
這樣啊
Hey, barkeep, can I ask you something?
老闆，可以問你一件事嗎？
How much is a hi-lite?
hi-lite是多少錢？
It's 170 yen.
170圓
I thought so.
我想也是
That's bad.
那滿糟的
Crap!
糟糕！
Rumpy-pumpy!
那檔子事！
Junko!
純子！
Why are you on top, huh?
為什麼是你在上面啊？
Won't you at least knock, you geezer?
老頭，你至少敲個門啦
How dare you!
你這混蛋！
Let go of me!
放開我！
Shut up, you sow! Wear your panties!
閉嘴，母豬！穿上內褲！
I haven't taken them off yet!
我還沒脫！
You were totally going to take them off! And you were even on top of him!
你這不是打算要脫嗎？ 你在上面幹什麼？
-Earlier, I was the one on top. -Did I ask?
-到剛才為止都是我在上面 -沒人問你！
Who the hell are you? A junior high student?!
你這小子是誰？你是國中生吧！
Yes. I'm Kiyoshi.
對，我是阿清
Kiyoshi from where?
哪來的阿清啊？
How long have you been dating her?
你們是從什麼時候開始交往的？
Today, I fell in love with Junko at first sight and came with her here.
我今天對純子學姐一見鍾情 所以跟著她過來
I'm Kiyoshi from Yonchome.
我是四丁目的阿清
You're not making a lick of sense. Do you even realize that?
你說的話很扯喔，你知道嗎？
Right. I don't think I do.
這個嘛，我不知道
Unbelievable.
不敢置信
I'd like to have a word with your parents.
真想看看你父母長怎樣
Hold on. Just a moment.
等一下，等等
Unbelievable. This kid is unbelievable.
不敢相信，太扯了
So, what do you like about Junko?
我問你，你喜歡純子的哪一點？
-Her looks and figure. -Say what?
-長相和身材 -你說什麼？
Say that again.
你再說一次試試看
Her looks and figure.
長相和身材
How dare you say it again!
你還真的給我再說一次！
-Hey! -Well, it was love at first sight.
-喂！ -因為啊，是一見鍾情嘛
Kiyoshi, let's run!
阿清，快逃！
Wait, you female gorilla!
站住，你這隻母猩猩！
-Hey! Come here! -Don't touch me!
-喂！給我過來！ -別碰我！
You know where hussies like you end up?
你覺得像你這種色女人 最後會有什麼下場？
On erotic photo books or in no-panties cafes!
就是拍色情雜誌 或去不穿內褲的咖啡廳工作啦！
Shut up, stupid shorty! And you call yourself my dad?
閉嘴，你這混帳矮子！ 這樣也算家長嗎？
Just wear your panties!
總之把內褲穿上！
I already am!
我有穿啊！
Are you? Show me!
有穿嗎？讓我看看！
Like hell I'll show you, moron!
怎麼可能讓你看，笨蛋！
ESSAY "YOUR FUTURE DREAM"
（作文“將來的夢想”）
Damn it. I still feel upset.
可惡，我還是很不爽
Even though she's at an age to be horny, I can't let my guard down at all.
雖然那小鬼處於性慾旺盛的青春期 但真的絲毫不能鬆懈
But what exactly happened the other day?
不過上次那場體驗到底是怎麼回事？
Was it a dream?
是一場夢嗎？
It must've been a dream.
肯定是我在作夢吧
After all, I'd hate a future like that.
畢竟誰會想要迎接那種未來啊？
SMOKING RAISES THE RISK OF CANCER
（抽菸容易導致肺癌）
Wait.
等等
It wasn't a dream.
那不是夢
I think I traveled to the future on a route bus.
我好像真的到了未來 是搭著公車去的
Mr. Ogawa, thank you for supervising them.
小川老師，謝謝你幫我顧他們
No problem.
不客氣
All right. Set your pencils down and pay attention.
各位，把筆放下，注意聽我說
I'll be introducing a transfer student.
我要介紹轉學生
All right, come on in.
好了，進來吧
All right, quiet down.
好，安靜
Because of his mother's business, he'll be in this class for a while.
他因為父母工作的關係 會在班上和我們學習一陣子
Introduce yourself.
自我介紹一下
I'm Kiyoshi Sakisaka. Nice to meet you all.
我是向坂清，請多指教
That over there is Mr. Ichiro Ogawa,
那位是學年主任兼副班導的
the head of year and assistant homeroom teacher.
小川市郎老師
He'll be instructing you in P.E. and welfare.
他負責教體育跟生活指導 好好接受教導吧
Okay…
好的
Nice to meet you, Kiyoshi.
請多指教，清同學
This here is your seat.
這是你的位子
I warmed it for you.
我已經幫你坐暖了
-Go ahead, take him up on his offer. -Come.
-來，你就接受他的好意 -過來吧
Come.
來吧…
Eek!
天哪！
"Eek"? What a cute reaction. Oh, you!
“天哪”？發出了可愛的聲音呢 你真是的…
You're done for, Kiyoshi.
你完了，阿清
Your youth is over.
你的青春走到盡頭了
Because you've met Ogawa in hell.
因為你在地獄見到小川了
Sakisaka, have you decided on a club activity?
向坂同學，你決定好社團了嗎？
Baseball club, right?
棒球社，對吧？
Say baseball club.
快說要參加棒球社啊
Baseball club.
棒球社
Don't dodge, ape!
別躲啊，猴子！
You ape!
你這猴子混帳！
Hey!
喂！
You sorry excuse for a man. You're like a namby-pamby girl.
明明是個男生，卻扭捏得像女人一樣
You bean sprout!
你這軟弱的豆芽菜！
Hey, do you even have balls?
喂，你真的有長蛋蛋嗎？
Hey!
嘿！
Get up, you ape!
給我站起來，你這猴子！
You want to have rumpy-pumpy?
想不想做那檔子事？
Huh?
說啊！
Yes.
我想做
How dare you! Shave your head!
想什麼想？去剪頭髮！
Shave your head by tomorrow!
明天前給我剃成光頭！
Oh! Well, well.
哦！你好…
I wasn't expecting to be able to talk to your parent this soon.
沒想到這麼快就能見到家長
So you're Ogawa, the power harassment teacher.
你就是那個叫小川的 職權騷擾教師啊？
S-Sour embarrassment?
“直拳效勞”教師？
Power harassment. You don't know that term, do you?
我是在說“職權騷擾” 你不知道啊？
In other words, it's abuse or bullying by a teacher.
那說是來自教師的虐待和霸凌 你就懂了吧
There, there, Mrs. Sakisaka.
別生氣，向坂太太
-Mr. Ogawa, take a seat. -Right.
-小川老師，你也坐下 -是
-Let's hear her out.
-我們聽一下她要說什麼 -好
He began shaving his head with hair clippers.
他竟然用電動剪髮器 開始剃自己的頭髮
I was so surprised. When I asked him why--
我嚇了一跳，問他為什麼…
You're smoking?!
你要抽菸嗎？
I heard you called him a sorry excuse for a man.
聽說你還批評他說 明明是男生卻怎樣
I did.
我的確說了
To be exact, I said, "You sorry excuse for a man."
正確來說是“明明是個男生
"You're like a namby-pamby girl. You bean sprout. Do you even have balls?"
卻扭捏得像女人一樣 你這軟弱的豆芽菜，有長蛋蛋嗎？”
Unbelievable!
難以置信！
Believe it or not, that's what I said.
不管你信不信，我的確說了
It's tough love, right?
是愛的鞭策吧？
Of course.
那是當然
I thought I'd whip him into shape.
我是想要重新鍛鍊他的毅力
Huh? Why are you nodding?
搞什麼？你在點什麼頭？
Do you think he can say anything in the name of tough love?
只要說是愛的鞭策 不管說什麼都可以嗎？
Okay, fine. You're so fussy. Next time, I'll punch him in silence.
好，知道了，一直講真囉嗦 下次我會閉嘴直接揍他
You punched him?
你揍了他嗎？
Not anywhere important.
沒有打到要害啦
I know that much. I'm a professional teacher, after all.
我有掌握分寸，我可是教育的專家
Tough love, right?
是愛的鞭策吧？
Please shut up!
你給我閉嘴！
Why are you in a tizzy?
為何脾氣這麼火爆？
Is it menopause? Sexual frustration?
更年期？欲求不滿？
Is your husband neglecting you?
是因為老公不理你嗎？
This bad, huh?
糟到這種程度啊？
I didn't anticipate the education scene in Showa to be this dismal.
沒想到昭和的教育現場竟然這麼誇張
At this stage, it's actually more fascinating than infuriating.
已經超過火大了 反而讓人覺得很有意思
Mrs. Sakisaka, you're a sociologist, right?
向坂太太是社會學者吧？
Oh, a highbrow. That's why you're so irritable.
原來如此，是知識分子才這麼乾癟啊
This is getting interesting, so let me record this.
事情越來越有趣了 所以請讓我錄音吧
Do you realize what was inappropriate about Mr. Ogawa's comments?
知道小川老師的發言哪裡不妥嗎？
Yes. Um…
知道，我想想…
-"You're like a namby-pamby girl." -And also, "You sorry excuse for a man."
-“扭捏得像女人一樣”… -也不能說“明明是個男生”
Stating that men or women should conform to certain stereotypes
男生要怎樣，女生要怎樣的刻板印象
is an unjust and discriminatory expression that harms young individuals.
是會不當傷害青少年的歧視言論
What else?
其他呢？
The rest was…
還有…
"You bean sprout" wasn't nice either.
說人家是“豆芽菜”也不好
-It harms bean sprout farmers… -What is this?
-會不當傷害豆芽菜農家 -這是什麼？
-Huh? -This thing.
-什麼？ -這個東西
This sleek thing.
這個光滑的東西
What is it? Where do they sell them?
這是什麼？哪裡有賣？
Hey! Stop that!
等一下！請住手！
Anyway, please understand that my son has a sensitive heart.
總之我家孩子的內心很細膩
Let's go.
回家吧
I was only intending to enroll him here temporarily.
雖然本來打算待一小段時間
But I can't leave my precious son
但我一天都不願意將寶貝兒子
at a school with such a violent teacher, not even for a day.
送到有這種暴力教師的學校
Hurry up!
動作快！
-I'll find another junior high-- -You can go first.
-我會找其他國中… -你先回去
I have club activities, so I'll be late.
我還有社團，會遲到
Kiyoshi, wait.
阿清，等等
-Kiyoshi! Wait. -Mrs. Sakisaka.
-阿清！站住 -向坂太太
-Please come back. -Kiyoshi, wait!
-請等一下 -阿清，等等我！
-Mrs. Sakisaka!
-向坂太太！
I want to know what that sleek gadget is!
好想知道那個 又光滑又薄的東西是什麼！
If it's a new product, it should be shown on 11 PM or Tonight.
如果是新商品 “11PM”或“TONIGHT”應該會介紹
Old man, when are you going to bed?
老頭，你幾點要睡？
You…
我說你啊
Are you only interested in when I come home and go to sleep?
除了問我幾點回家跟幾點睡之外 對我就一點興趣也沒有嗎？
What do you take me for?
把我當什麼了？
A shabby piggy bank.
髒兮兮的存錢筒
You weren't this way before, Junko.
純子，在你媽媽還活著的時候
Back when your mom was still with us.
你本來不是這個樣子
How about watching a video?
要看錄影帶嗎？
It's of you at ten, singing a Pink Lady song after a bath.
有拍下十歲那時候 你洗完澡唱著粉紅淑女的歌的樣子
Watch this and remember your past self.
看了這個之後回歸初衷吧
Like hell I'll watch it.
誰要看啊
Anyway, did you get a cassette for me?
不說這個，你買磁帶回來了嗎？
Yeah. Right there.
有買啊，在那邊
What is this?
這是什麼？
You wanted it, didn't you? What was it called again?
你不是說很想要嗎？叫什麼來著？
It's the outfit the Onyanko girls wear, with the sailor.
小貓俱樂部的人穿的 有印海軍圖案的
The Sailors? No way!
SAILORS？不會吧！
The Sailors sweatshirt, right?
SAILORS的運動衫
I found it so I bought one.
我有看到就買了
Are you serious? You're not all bad, after all!
真的嗎？你也有優點嘛
I splurged.
花了我好多錢呢
You handled the cleaning and took out the trash for me this month.
因為這個月你有幫我打掃和倒垃圾
This is a normal tape!
這不是一般的磁帶嗎？
What?
什麼？
I told you to get AXIA's chrome or metal tape, didn't I?
我說過要AXIA的鉻磁帶 或是金屬磁帶吧？
I'm giving this to a senior student, so I need the recording to sound good.
我要送給學長 所以想要錄下好一點的音質
I don't want a normal tape. Get it replaced!
我不要一般磁帶，你去換貨！
Who cares about the sound?
這跟音質哪有關係
It's a Shibugakitai song, anyway.
反正你是要錄苦柿隊的歌吧
Anyway, try the Sailors shirt on.
別管了，快穿看看SAILORS的衣服吧
Where did you get this?
這是在哪裡買的？
Kinshicho.
錦糸町
What?
什麼？
They only sell Sailors shirts in Shibuya.
SAILORS牌的衣服只有澀谷有在賣
They don't have them in Kinshicho. Look carefully, geezer!
才沒有來錦糸町開店呢 你給我看清楚，老頭！
"Sayers"?
“SAYERS”？
It says "Sayers." Damn it.
這是“SAYERS”啦，可惡
It's a fake. They got me.
是假貨，我被騙了
I don't want it. Go return it.
我不要穿，你拿去退貨
No, it's cool.
不，這很帥吧
I mean, it's saying Seiya!
上頭的人物邊大喊“看招！” 一邊出拳
No one else is wearing something like this.
沒有其他人會穿這種衣服喔
This is Ogawa.
這裡是小川家
Hello?
喂？
Who is this?
你是哪位？
Junko took a crap and went to bed.
要找純子的話，她拉完屎就睡了
Hey!
喂！
It's time for kids to go to bed! Moron!
小鬼的睡覺時間到了，笨蛋！
Take a crap and go to bed yourself, geezer!
你這老頭，也快點去拉屎 然後睡覺吧！
Hey!
喂！
Who's that scruffy punk resembling a female mantis?
那個長得像母螳螂的 寒酸小混混是誰？
He's nothing like Kiyoshi from Yonchome!
那根本就不是四丁目的阿清嘛！
So, you're cool with anyone for rumpy-pumpy?
只要能做那檔子事 不管對象是誰都可以嗎？
Hey!
喂！
Junko.
純子
Sorry about earlier.
剛剛真抱歉
I'll get you a proper Sailors shirt, okay?
之後我會去買真的 SAILORS的衣服給你，好嗎？
Junko dear?
親愛的純子？
Are you asleep?
你睡了嗎？
She's asleep.
她睡著了…
JUNKO 1978 PINK LADY
（純子，1978 粉紅淑女）
F*CK TO THE TEACHER RURU AIDA
（《上到老師》 愛田露露）
Damn!
可惡！
I apologize for the late call.
抱歉在夜裡打擾
I'm a member of the Miss Magazine selection committee.
我是Miss Magazine的選拔委員會
Miss Junko has been selected as--
這次純子小姐被我們選為…
You're Kiyoshi from Yonchome.
你是四丁目的阿清吧？
It's so obvious.
太明顯了吧
You still have energy left after all those bunny hops this afternoon?
白天跳了那麼久的兔子跳 你現在還有體力啊？
Tomorrow, I'll have you do twice as many.
明天叫你加倍跳
You're still awake?
你還醒著啊？
Sorry.
抱歉
Just unbelievable.
真是難以相信
They're showing boobs on terrestrial TV!
明明是無線電視，卻有女生露點！
Go to bed now. We're heading home tomorrow.
快睡吧，明天就要回去了
Tomorrow?
明天？
The earlier, the better, right?
越早回去越好吧？
This era is too tough for you.
這個年代對你來說太難熬了
Come on. Turn the light off already.
來，快點關燈
Goodnight.
晚安
"My future dream is to become a globally recognized scientist."
我將來的夢想是 成為世界第一的科學家
-"In the past, many scientists have…" -He probably transferred again.
-過去有許多科學家… -他又轉學了吧？
What, really? That's so sudden.
真的嗎？這麼突然
"YOUR FUTURE DREAM" PRESENTATION
（“將來的夢想”）
That sleek thing wasn't shown on 11 PM or Tonight.
那個又光滑又薄的東西 “11PM”或“TONIGHT”都沒有介紹
Which means, maybe
果然就表示…
it really was a dream.
那是一場夢
That day,
在那一天
when I stepped off the bus after my club activities, it was…
社團結束後打算回家的我 下了公車，然後看到…
I just heard that.
我剛才聽說了
Say cheese.
笑一個
And there, I met her.
而且在那裡遇到了她
That was one good woman.
她真是個好女人
But for some reason, she seemed unhappy.
但感覺好像不是很幸福
Can't a mother with a baby enjoy even a single glass of beer?
難道帶嬰兒的母親 連喝杯啤酒都不行嗎？
I'm curious about her
好在意她的事
but I can't see her again.
但我已經見不到她了
"Are you familiar with the movie Back to the Future?"
各位知道《回到未來》這部電影嗎？
"I've seen it 18 times."
我看了18次
I want to see her.
好想見到她
I can't believe I didn't at least ask for her number.
真是失策啊 當時至少該跟她要個電話才對
"The protagonist uses a time machine to travel to a world 30 years in the past."
主角搭乘時光機前往30年前的世界
"The time machine, constructed by Doc,
博士製造的時光機
is a dimension transfer device installed in a DeLorean DMC-12 car and--"
是由德羅寧DMC-12跑車 搭載次元轉移裝置…
-You're not making any sense, nerd! -Shut up!
-沒人聽得懂啦，書呆子！ -閉嘴！
Hey, four-eyes. Can a time machine be built?
喂，眼鏡仔 時光機是做得出來的嗎？
My name is Inoue.
我是井上
In theory, it's considered not impossible.
理論上，據說並非不可能
Einstein proposed that
愛因斯坦說
the third-dimensional space is linked with time.
將三次元的空間和時間連結
-Which functions as the fourth-- -Forget it. I won't understand anyway.
-再把時間當作四次元… -好，閉嘴，反正我聽不懂
Just tell me if it's possible.
只要告訴我做不做得出來
I believe it is.
我認為可以
If you work hard enough.
只要努力就能做到
Work hard, Inoue. You can do it.
加油啊，井上，你一定可以做到的
-Right! -Right.
-好的！ -好
My dream is to become a scientist, invent a time machine,
我的夢想是成為科學家，發明時光機
and journey back 30 years into the past to revisit Class B, Grade 2 at School 6.
從30年後的未來 穿越到現在的六中2年B班
Was the bus I took that day a time machine?
我當時搭的公車就是時光機嗎？
So, by taking the same bus, I can travel to the future.
只要搭上跟當時同一輛公車 就能前往未來
Right?
是嗎？
Two buses within an hour.
一小時兩班車
Which one did I board?
我搭的是哪班？
Three, three-thirty…
“3點、3點30分”
Are you scared, Junko?
你不會怕吧？純子
No. Let's go!
不會，衝啊…
Kiyoshi, let's go.
阿清，要走囉
Is it this bus?
是這班嗎？
We're getting on!
我們要上車！
How?
怎麼會？
Hey, Kiyoshi!
等等，阿清！
Kiyoshi, wait! Kiyoshi!
阿清，等一下！阿清！
Mrs. Sakisaka, you dropped this!
向坂太太，你掉了這個！
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Stop, Kiyoshi!
給我等一下，阿清！
Stop!
站住！
Wait, we're getting on!
等一下，我們要上車！
-Stop the bus! Some people want to board! -We're getting on!
-停下來！還有人要上車！ -我們要上車！
I said stop the bus! Hey!
我叫你停下來！喂！
Stop!
等等！
-No, Mrs. Sakisaka, it won't stop! -Stop!
-沒辦法！向坂太太，停不下來！ -別開走啊！
The driver is a mannequin!
司機是假人！
No, it won't stop! No!
沒辦法，無法停車！不行！
Stop!
等等我！
I've fallen in love.
我有喜歡的人了
What?!
什麼？
So,
所以啊
I want to stay here longer.
我想再多待一下
Sorry.
抱歉
Stop right there. Kiyoshi!
你給我站住，阿清！
-Let go of me. -Who is this person?
-放開我 -你喜歡的人是誰？
-Where is this person from? -Let go of me, old biddy!
-哪裡的人？ -放開我，老太婆！
I don't want to go back to Reiwa! I like the Showa era!
我才不想回到令和，我就是喜歡昭和
Why?
為什麼？
What's to like about this era?
這種時代有哪裡好了？
It's rough and full of discrimination and adults with no taste.
充滿了粗暴和歧視 都是些沒水準的大人
You get to see boobs on TV!
不是能在電視上看到胸部嗎？
What happened to you?
你是怎麼回事？
I want to see boobs on TV!
我想在電視上看女生的胸部！
I want to see boobs on terrestrial TV!
我想在無線電視上看胸部！
I want to see them!
我想看！
I beg your pardon.
不好意思
I know.
我很清楚
Something's wrong with me.
我可能哪裡出了問題
So just leave me alone.
所以別管我
I went too far by calling you an old biddy.
叫你“老太婆”太超過了
I'm sorry.
對不起
DRINKS
（飲料）
Here is your Broiled Shime Saba.
您點的炙燒醋漬鯖魚來了
Should I get you the same drink?
點一樣的飲料可以嗎？
I'll order one myself.
我自己來
Anyway, are you sure you have no clue?
別說這個了，你真的沒頭緒嗎？
No.
沒有
I admired Kaga, after all.
我對加賀期望很高
She's working toward having the case seen as power harassment.
對方打算指控你職權騷擾
Did she really say that?
她真的說了嗎？
That she had a mental…
她的內心…
That she had a mental breakdown.
她的內心已經到極限了
That's undeniable.
毫無疑問
She's taking a month-long leave of absence.
好像要休職一個月
Here is your Broiled Shime Saba.
您點的炙燒醋漬鯖魚來了
Shall we practice for the personnel department interview?
我們來為人事部的質問調查 做模擬練習吧
"He put pressure on me just before my presentation."
“在發表前被施加壓力”
Does that ring any bells?
你有做過這種事嗎？
It's soon, isn't it, Kaga? I expect a lot from you, so work hard!
終於要發表了呢，加賀 期待你的表現，加油
Right.
好的
Wait. Can't I even offer encouragement?
什麼？替對方打氣也不行嗎？
It can cause some people to have a breakdown.
有些人會因此受挫
That will be seen as power harassment. Say that it was a thoughtless remark.
這認定是職權騷擾，講話過於輕率
What's next?
接著是什麼？
Well then, Kaga, take care of the support tasks.
那麼加賀，幫忙記錄支援內容
Right.
是
You're so fast.
打字速度好快啊
Leave it to Generation Z.
不愧是Z世代
I did say that.
我的確說了
She really is fast at flick input, though.
但她打字真的很快
What? I can't say that?
什麼？這樣也不行？
Labeling someone based on their generation falls under age harassment.
用世代區分是年齡騷擾
Here is your Broiled Shime Saba.
您點的炙燒醋漬鯖魚來了
Broiled Shime Saba is really popular, huh?
炙燒醋漬鯖魚真受歡迎呢
Shall we order a plate?
我們也點吧
And what else?
還有什麼？
It seems you've even made a sexual harassment remark, Akitsu.
你好像也說了性騷擾的話，秋津
No, that's impossible. There's no way.
不，沒這回事，絕對沒有
You had a barbecue with members of the sales department, right?
聽說業務部的年輕人一起去烤肉了？
Here you go.
請用
Thanks.
謝謝
Any guy who gets you as a wife is lucky.
能娶加賀的男人真幸福
She felt awkward
當時氣氛變得像是
as it sounded you were labeling the other females as inconsiderate.
在指責沒動手的 其他女性員工很不細心，場面尷尬
I didn't intend it that way.
我不是那個意思
Regardless of the intent,
不管你的想法是什麼
if it made the other person uncomfortable, it's harassment.
只要對方感到不愉快，那就是騷擾
In these times, even compliments need to be given with caution.
畢竟就是這樣的時代嘛 稱讚時也要謹言慎行呢
What kind of times?
哪種時代？
Pardon?
什麼？
You're the fourth person I've heard say "in these times."
你已經是第四個說 “畢竟就是這樣的時代嘛”的人了
And I've been drinking here since this place opened.
我從開店時就在這裡喝了
Here is your Broiled Shime Saba.
您點的炙燒醋漬鯖魚來了
No way. I've only had one glass so far.
不會吧，我才只喝一杯耶
I've been trying to get another glass of lemon sour,
我從剛才就在加點檸檬沙瓦
but all I'm getting is Broiled Shime Saba. What did I do, huh?
但卻一直上炙燒醋漬鯖魚 我是做了什麼嗎？
Can I help?
我來幫你點吧
I'd appreciate that.
幫大忙了
I can tell that the economy isn't doing great.
我是有感覺到景氣不好
The part-timers' hourly wages haven't improved.
畢竟打工的時薪沒漲
You've ordered 200 plates of Broiled Shime Saba.
你點了兩百份炙燒醋漬鯖魚
Just kill me already.
乾脆殺了我吧
So, what kind of times are these?
所以呢？是什麼時代？
It's an era of diversity.
是講求多樣性的時代
Having a happy life isn't just about getting married.
不是只有結婚才能過得幸福
And it's an era where if someone tells you to work hard,
還有，被人講了“加油”
you can take a month off from work?
就能向公司請假一個月的時代？
No offense, but please don't mind us.
抱歉，這是我們公司的事 請你別在意
We've met before.
我們之前見過面吧
What?
什麼？
This one.
-給你 -我要這罐
The sound really is different.
音質果然不同
Nothing beats metal tapes.
金屬磁帶最讚了
Hey, Mutchy.
我說啊，阿睦學長
Don't you notice anything?
有沒有注意到什麼？
What?
什麼？
Come on, look again.
真是的，你仔細看一下
I don't get it.
我不曉得
My bangs.
我的瀏海
I styled them after Akina on the jacket of "Desire."
我捲成明菜在“DESIRE”裡的樣子
More than Akina, I totally…
其實比起明菜…
like Miyuki Imori better.
我比較喜歡井森美幸
Did you want the milk tea?
喝奶茶比較好嗎？
This isn't bitter.
才不苦呢
Junko,
純子
do you want kids?
你想要孩子嗎？
What?
什麼？
I don't know. I haven't thought of that yet.
那種事我還不曉得
If I have a son,
如果生了男孩
I'll raise him to be a fearless kid who never loses in a fight.
我要把他教成打架不會輸 勇敢無懼的孩子
That'd be…
那樣…
awesome.
超棒的耶
If you want, I'll stop being a punk.
你希望的話，我也可以不當不良少年
So Junko,
所以純子
won't you give me your future?
把你的未來交給我好嗎？
Kiyoshi?
阿清？
D…
不…
Don't touch my woman.
不准對我的女人出手
Who the hell are you?
你是什麼人？
Junko and I…
我跟純子…
have a very fine relationship.
正在交往中
Bring it on!
你很敢嘛！
What?
什麼？
The dishes are brought by a robot, but it's a human who broils them.
端來的是機器人 但幫忙炙燒的是人類啊
I canceled the remaining Shime Saba for you.
我取消炙燒醋漬鯖魚的訂單了
-And you want a lemon sour, right? -Yeah.
-然後要點檸檬沙瓦對吧？ -對
The one who takes a break from work after being encouraged gains sympathy,
因為被說了“加油” 而請假的員工被大家同情
but this guy who offered the encouragement gets criticized.
但卻責備替對方加油的他
It sounds messed up.
是不是有哪裡不太對？
What was he supposed to say, then?
不然他該說什麼才好？
He shouldn't have said anything.
什麼都不要說才好
He should've silently watched over her.
什麼都不要說，靜靜守望部下
After it went well,
做得好的話
he could've complimented her in a way that wouldn't make her feel pressured.
就要在不讓對方有壓力的情況下稱讚
He should never criticize a mistake.
即使犯錯了也絕不責備
If he had empathized with her and helped identify the cause of the mistake,
只要貼近對方的心情 一起思考原因的話
she wouldn't have had a breakdown.
她就不會受挫了
Revolting.
真噁心
Pardon?
什麼？
What do you mean by empathize? As if you're Mutsugoro.
什麼叫貼近對方的心？ 自以為是陪伴動物的彈塗魚先生啊？
This is why hourly wages don't improve and the economy is struggling.
就是因為那樣時薪才沒漲 景氣還變差了吧
Plus, jobs are being taken over by robots.
到最後還被機器人搶了工作
Here is your Broiled Bacon.
您點的炙燒培根來了
Robots don't have breakdowns,
畢竟機器人犯錯了
even if they make a mistake, after all.
也不會覺得挫折嘛
Sorry.
不好意思
That's weird.
真奇怪
Give me a break!
開什麼玩笑？
We weren't working so hard
就為了這種未來！
to bring about this future or these times.
我們之所以拼命工作 才不是為了造就這種時代！
You have expectations of people, and you meet their expectations.
期待他人，並回應期待
You receive criticism and encouragement, and you work hard.
被人斥責，受人鼓勵後繼續加油
That's how you become stronger. That's the essence of being human.
人類就要像這樣互相產生關聯 並變得堅強吧
That idea is outdated.
這種想法已經過時了
Mental something or whatever.
我不管對方內心受挫還是怎樣
If receiving encouragement gets you down,
不過被人說了句“加油”就受挫的人
you won't last long anyway.
反正也做不久啦
That kind of remark is exactly what's problematic right now!
那種言論在這時代是最糟糕的！
"That kind of remark is exactly what's problematic right now!"
“那種言論在這時代是最糟糕的！”
But it's fine to end the conversation by yelling hysterically?
歇斯底里地喊出這句話後 就結束話題，這樣就可以？
Doesn't that qualify as some form of harassment?
這不算是什麼騷擾嗎？
What would you do?
如果是你，會怎麼做？
Don't engage him.
別跟他認真啦，秋津
If someone makes a mistake? Let's see.
若有人犯錯我會怎樣？我想想喔
I'd spank them with a bat.
犯錯就用球棒打屁股
And if they do well?
對方做得好的話呢？
Toss them in the air.
把對方拋起來歡呼
I like that.
真不錯
Let's leave.
走吧
Let's continue this conversation.
不再多談談嗎？
Talking with someone like him won't lead to anything.
跟這種大叔談也不會有結果的啦
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Even if we can't understand each other…
即使不能互相理解
Hey. What's gotten into you?
喂，怎麼了？
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Especially with an old guy like him
正因為他是這種大叔
Unlike robots, it's something we can do
我們不是機器人，所以才能這麼做
We can have a conversation
那就是互相溝通
What is it? What's gotten into you?
搞什麼？你怎麼了？
A junior colleague, whom I treated with care to avoid power harassment,
我有一個很器重的後輩 雖然我有小心地避免職權騷擾
left the company last year.
但對方仍在去年離職了
He said he was going to a convenience store,
說要去一趟便利商店，從此沒回來
and he ended up a YouTuber.
後來竟跑去當YouTuber
Screw him.
開什麼玩笑？
Screw him, that bastard!
開什麼玩笑？那個混帳！
Was that Hitoshi Ueki? No? What's up with you?
植木等？不對嗎？你是怎麼回事？
No guidance from above
上頭什麼都沒教我們
But beneath, eggshells
卻說部下是易碎品
Tread carefully
小心別傷害他們
In my seventh year with the company
今年是我進公司的第7年
My mental health has reached its limit
內心早就已經瀕臨極限
So let's have a conversation
所以我們好好談一談吧
It's time!
現在正是時候！
Broiled Shime Saba
炙燒醋漬鯖魚
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Let's have a conversation today
今天就讓我們好好談一談吧
Broiled Shime Saba
炙燒醋漬鯖魚
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
True, you're right about everything
沒錯，無論何時你都是對的
What, you too?
什麼？你也要跟著唱？
But what's right isn't always right
但是對的事並不一定是對的
That's organizations for you
那便是組織
Any justice if brandished Turns into oppression
無論是基於怎樣的正義 只要大肆濫用就等於對人施壓
That's organizations for you
那便是組織
So don't assert yourself
所以不要固執己見
Or have expectations
也不要期待他人
In my 13th year with the company
今年是我進公司的第13年
My mental health is long gone
內心早就已經死透了
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Broiled Shime Saba
炙燒醋漬鯖魚
I won't talk with you
我拒絕討論
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Broiled Shime Saba
炙燒醋漬鯖魚
I won't talk with you
我拒絕討論
That's organizations for you
那便是組織
If you won't exchange words
不願好好談一談的話
Why not exchange blows?
那就互毆對方吧
Fist against fist
拳拳相對
Let them speak for you!
藉此交流就行了！
Oh…
真是的
Give up.
放棄吧
Mutchy!
阿睦學長！
Not bad.
你很行嘛
You said, "Having a happy life isn't just about getting married."
你剛才說“不是只有結婚 才能過得幸福”
But does that mean you can't say, "I'm happy I got married"?
那也不能說“我結婚了 我過得很幸福”嗎？
I was happy when I married my missus.
我跟老婆結婚時很幸福喔
When my daughter was born, I was so happy I wanted to shout.
女兒出生時甚至幸福到想大叫出聲
Why hold yourself back?
不用忍耐也可以啊
A society where you can't express Your happiness
連自己幸福都很難說出口的社會
Isn't something wrong with that?
不覺得哪邊不對勁嗎？
That's diversity for you
那就是多樣性啊
A society that embraces diverse perspectives.
這是一個包容多樣價值觀的社會
So, accept my perspective too, and let me declare my happiness.
那你也該認同 我大喊出很幸福的價值觀
That's real diversity
那才是真正的多樣性
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Fist against fist
拳拳相對
Even if we can't understand each other
即使不能互相理解
There will be a record of us having talked
也會留下討論過的紀錄
If a conversation won't lead us anywhere, singing won't be of any help either.
但連討論都沒結果了 在這裡唱歌也沒用
Isn't it late to say that?
事到如今才說這些？
Are you satisfied now?
滿意了嗎？
Well then, good luck with the interview tomorrow.
那明天的質問調查會議 再麻煩你參加了
Let's have a conversation
我們好好談一談吧
Kaga?
加賀？
I'm sorry, Mr. Akitsu. I…
對不起，秋津前輩，我…
What is it?
怎麼了？
I wanted you to scold me
我當時是想被你斥責
You were known for being strict with the other employees.
前輩對其他員工都是嚴厲指導 因此很出名
But when it came to me, you said, "Work hard,"
但只對我說“加油”
"I have expectations for you,"
“期待你的表現”
and other ambiguous things.
總是這種模稜兩可的話
So I thought you didn't see me as a part of the team from the start.
所以我以為你打從一開始 就不把我看在眼裡
That's not true.
不是那樣的
Because I'm a woman
因為我是女性
I thought you had given up on me
所以前輩放棄我了
That's not true
不對…
It is true
沒有錯
It's because you're outstanding
是因為你非常優秀
I've never experienced that.
被人斥責的經驗
Not once
從來都沒有
Not even by my parents
就連父母也沒罵過我
Not by anyone
從來沒人訓斥過我
If we were to scold you, it would be power harassment.
斥責下屬就會演變成職權騷擾啊
Regardless of the reason. That's why we're too scared to scold you.
不管是出於什麼理由 所以我們怕得不敢罵人
That's organizations for you
那便是組織
Still,
即使如此
I wanted to be scolded.
我也想被斥責
Really?
真的嗎？
Are you sure we can scold you?
真的可以斥責你嗎？
-By Mr. Akitsu. -Of course. Go ahead.
-我是想被秋津前輩罵 -也對，請吧
There's nothing to scold you about.
你沒有可以斥責的地方
You're fine the way you are.
你只要保持現在這樣就好了
I'm sorry.
對不起
I may have just wanted your attention.
我可能只是希望你多注意我
That's hard to tell unless you tell me.
你不說的話我不會曉得啊
I'm glad we could have a conversation
幸好有好好溝通
-Hey. -Sorry. I don't have any cash.
-等一下 -抱歉，我沒帶錢
I'll cover it for you.
我會替你結帳
Thanks.
幫大忙了
I have to hurry, or my daughter will have rumpy-pumpy.
我不快點回去的話 女兒又要做那檔子事了
Not bad.
你很行嘛
Sort of.
還可以啦
The hole in the toilet. To the toilet.
廁所的洞，去廁所吧…
To the toilet…
廁所…
Oh.
啊
Hey.
你好
You came.
來了
I thought I'd be able to see you if I waited here.
我就知道在這裡等就能見到你
What?
什麼？
You want a drink?
要什麼飲料？
Beer, then.
那就啤酒
This is where you work?
你在這邊工作啊？
At night, this place becomes a hostess bar.
對，這裡在晚間時段是小酒館
By the way, mister.
對了，大哥
It's Ogawa.
我姓小川
Mr. Ogawa, you're getting bashed on socials.
小川先生，你引起輿論撻伐了
Socials?
輿論撻伐？
-This is you, right? -You're the one risking danger, miss.
-這是你吧？ -妹妹才比較危險
Udon noodles are hanging from your ears, and your panties are almost showing.
有烏龍麵從耳朵垂下來 還穿這種快看到內褲的裙子
You should be careful of saying stuff like this.
這種事還是小心點比較好
Once it's out there online, you can't just hit delete.
被傳到網路上就刪不掉了
-It's called a digital tattoo-- -This thing…
-這就叫做數位刺青… -這東西…
So it's a TV.
原來是電視啊
Not exactly.
也不能那麼說啦
It's more like a phone, wallet, radio,
算是電話，可以當成錢包或收音機
and camera.
還能當相機
I have one too. The same one.
我也有同樣的東西
Huh?
奇怪？
Huh? Wait a minute.
怪了，等我一下
Looking for this?
是在找這個嗎？
That's it.
對
Thanks for bringing it to me.
謝謝你特地送過來
This is it.
就是這個
I-Is something the matter?
怎麼了嗎？
Well, um…
這個嘛…
You probably won't believe me,
你們可能不相信
but I come from Showa 61.
但我是從昭和61年來的
W-What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Through time strip.
我“脫”越時空了
Don't you know?
不知道嗎？
There's a movie called Back to the Whatchamacallit.
就像那部開頭是《回到》的電影
I'm here from 38 years ago.
我是從38年前來的
Which means, you guys are people of the future.
也就是說，你們是未來人
I'm a P.E. teacher at School 6 and the baseball club staff adviser.
我是六中的體育老師 也是棒球社的顧問
I'm known as Ogawa from Hell.
人稱“地獄小川”
This is my student's lost item.
這是我的學生弄掉的東西
Sorry, see you again.
抱歉，下次再聊
My daughter might have rumpy-pumpy.
不然我女兒要做那檔子事了
Where's Kyon Kyon?
Kyon Kyon呢？
Where's Kyon Kyon's poster?
Kyon Kyon的海報呢？
Why?
搞什麼？
Want to come over?
要來我家嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
You need to get this treated properly.
要好好幫你擦藥才行
Don't worry.
不用擔心
My dad isn't home today.
今天我老爸不在家
Let's go.
走吧
Where's Kyon Kyon?!
Kyon Kyon呢？
Kyon Kyon?
Kyon Kyon？
The toilet! It's a Western-style one now!
廁所！變成坐式的了！
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊
We had a dealer install a Washlet today.
我們今天請業者來換成免治馬桶了
Today? Why?
今天？為什麼？
Well, because having a Japanese-style toilet is outdated.
哪有為什麼，現在哪有人在用蹲式的
And the barkeep says he has hemorrhoids.
而且老闆說他痔瘡變嚴重了
What the hell, you ugly?!
你搞什麼啊？醜女！
Excuse me?!
你說什麼？
She's going to have rumpy-pumpy!
她要做那檔子事了啦！
My daughter is going to have rumpy…
我女兒要做那檔子事…
Huh?
什麼？
Shall we watch something?
要不要看些什麼？
Like a video of me when I was little
有一捲錄影帶拍下我小時候洗完澡
dancing to Pink Lady with my mom after a bath.
和媽媽一起跳粉紅淑女歌曲的舞
Of you, Junko?
純子學姐跳舞嗎？
I want to see it.
我想看…
F*CK TO THE TEACHER
（《上到老師》）
JUNKO 1978 PINK LADY
（純子，1978 粉紅淑女）
Damn it. I screwed up!
可惡，搞砸了！
MOM
（媽媽）
VIDEO CALL
（媽媽，視訊通話）
Hello?
喂？
Is that… Ogawa?
是小川老師嗎？
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃琴喻
What the hell is a "work style"?
“工作風格”是什麼鬼東西？
They'll reprimand me for making you work unpaid overtime!
讓下屬無償加班我會被罵的！
Don't try to carry everything on your own.
不要什麼事都想一肩扛下
After a one-on-one fight, you become buddies.
既然曾經一對一決鬥過 我們就是死黨了
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Anything you can do, I can pretty much do too.
再說你能做的事，我也幾乎都能做
Let me choose my own work style, at least!
至少該讓人自己決定工作方式吧！